[{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"1. Vacuum polarization results from a pair of particles with this property screening charges. Particles with this property are responsible for the non-zero parts of the propagator outside the light cone. Particles with this property are said to be “off-shell” because they do not satisfy the normal energy–momentum relations, and they are often described as vacuum fluctuations in quantum fields. In one formulation, Hawking radiation results from particles of this type being “boosted” by the gravitation of a black hole. The lifetime of these particles is limited by the uncertainty principle. A wavy line between two vertices in a QED diagram corresponds to a photon with this property. For 10 points, name this type of particle that produces forces when they are exchanged by ordinary particles and are sometimes said to “pop in and out of existence.” ","answer":"ANSWER: virtual particles [accept off-shell particles or off-mass-shell particles until read; prompt on gauge bosons or photons by asking “what characteristic do those particles have in this situation?”] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"2. One of this playwright’s characters claims to have lived for two years off of his misfortunes, such as losing the use of his limbs and becoming a “widow with six helpless children.” In a play by this author, a woman described as an “old weather-beaten she-dragon” serves as the guardian of an heiress who loves “Ensign Beverly,” who is actually another man in disguise. The second act of a play by this author features many comments from Mr. Sneer and Mr. Dangle, who are watching a rehearsal of the tragedy The Spanish Armada. In a play by this author, Charles Surface throws down the screen covering Lady Teazle, whom her husband and Charles had believed to be a French milliner. This author of The Critic wrote a play about Jack Absolute’s pursuit of Lydia Languish, the niece of Mrs. Malaprop. For 10 points, name this author of The School for Scandal and The Rivals. ","answer":"ANSWER: Richard Brinsley Sheridan <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"3. During this dynasty, a compilation of surnames in a common quatrain rhyming scheme, called the Hundred Family Surnames, was composed. A detailed map of China’s coast and rivers with a grid superimposed onto it was carved into a stele (“STEE-lee”) in Xi’an (“shee-ahn”) during this dynasty. A popular general from this dynasty who was executed after Qin Hui (“cheen hway”) betrayed him was named Yue Fei (“y’weh fay”). After the Humiliation of Jingkang ended this dynasty’s Northern era, this dynasty moved capitals from Kaifeng (“kye-fung”) to Hangzhou (“hong-joe”) to avoid Jurchen raids. After it lost the six-year-long siege of Xiangyang (“sh’yong-yong”), the last remnants of this dynasty were defeated at the Battle of Yamen (“ya-mun”) by the forces of Kublai Khan. For 10 points, name this dynasty that invented gunpowder but was nevertheless defeated by the Mongols. ","answer":"ANSWER: Song Dynasty <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"4. This architect used a hollow concrete shaft with a diameter of 4.5 meters to support a ten-story pod in his guy-wire-supported Torre de Collserola (“TORR-uh the cool-suh-RAW-luh”). One of his buildings incorporates a cast-stone base designed by Joseph Urban and features a “diagrid” façade that forms huge concave corner window structures known as “bird’s mouths.” This architect designed the world’s tallest bridge, the Millau (“mee-YO”) Viaduct, as well as Manhattan’s Hearst Tower. He placed a mirror-paneled cone surrounded by two helical ramps under a cupola (“KYOO-puh-luh”) that he added to a building that was wrapped by Jean-Claude and Christo before its 1990s reconstruction. Swiss Re (“ree”) is the primary occupant of a skyscraper he designed at 30 St Mary Axe that is popularly known as “the Gherkin.” For 10 points, name this British high-tech architect who restored the Reichstag (“RIKE-stog”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Norman Foster [or Norman Robert Foster; or Baron Foster of Thames Bank] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"5. A work by this thinker argues for removing the Freudian notion of “wish-fulfillment” from the domain of individual biography to understand how all artworks are “vital episodes in a single vast unfinished plot.” This thinker, who opened that book with the command to “Always historicize!”, argued in a different work that the “curiously unmarked” entrances to the Bonaventure Hotel in Los Angeles fail to fulfill the “aesthetic populism” of a certain movement’s rhetoric. This author of The Political Unconscious described how the neutral mode of pastiche (“pass-TEESH”) has replaced the function of parody in criticizing an aesthetic and philosophical movement as the expression of American dominance in global capitalism. For 10 points, name this Marxist author of Postmodernism: The Cultural Logic of Late Capitalism. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fredric Jameson <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"6. The Samuelson condition locates the point at which the marginal cost of providing things described by this adjective equals the individual’s marginal rate of substitution. Richard Musgrave developed his “three-branch model” in a book titled for this type of finance. As part of his work in a field of economic theory named for this adjective, Gordon Tullock analyzed how special interests secure profits through a process of “rent-seeking” and co-authored a book that outlined many of its key principles, The Calculus of Consent. The economist James Buchanan was best-known for his work in that field, whose name pairs this adjective with “choice.” This adjective describes a type of good that is both non-excludable and non-rivalrous, an example of which is clean air. For 10 points, name this term that denotes parts of the economy controlled by the government, unlike the private sector. ","answer":"ANSWER: public [accept public goods, public finance, A Theory of Public Finance, public choice theory, and the public sector] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"4. Bus 37 with its clock stopped at 10:25 a.m. memorializes a 1980 bombing of a train station in this country that killed 85 people. This is the first country in which the term “strategy of tension” was used to refer to the policy of encouraging extremist violence. Factory workers in the north of this country went on strike in a period called the Hot Autumn. A clandestine NATO stay-behind operation in this country was called Operation Gladio. Students and police clashed at a university in this country’s capital in the Battle of Valle Giulia (“vahl-lay JOO-lee-ah”). The Red Brigades kidnapped and killed this country’s prime minister Aldo Moro during its Years of Lead. For 10 points, name this country whose recent prime ministers have included Silvio Berlusconi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Italy [or Italian Republic; or Italia] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"8. The central family in this novel goes to Vincent’s once a month to eat baked ziti. A character in this novel wears a veil made from the bottom of an old stocking, which she says helps prevent her stuttering. The protagonist of this novel makes his fortune by taking over his father’s luxury glove factory. That protagonist has an affair with his daughter’s speech therapist, Sheila Salzman. Rita Cohen sexually taunts the protagonist of this novel, and helps him locate his missing daughter. In this novel, a former Miss New Jersey named Dawn Dwyer gets a facelift to impress the architect Bill Orcutt, with whom she has an affair. Prior to the action of this novel, Merry plants a bomb in a post office in protest of the Vietnam War. Nathan Zuckerman narrates, for 10 points, what novel about Seymour “The Swede” Levov’s supposedly idyllic life, written by Philip Roth? ","answer":"ANSWER: American Pastoral <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"9. P Cygni (“SIG-nee”) profiles are spectroscopic features caused by this phenomenon. This phenomenon can be “driven” by photon absorption by particular spectral lines. It’s not an accretion disk, but a magnetic field forces this phenomenon to co-rotate with its source when it is within the Alfvén (“all-VANE”) radius. The “fast” form of this phenomenon forms from open regions of a magnetic field called coronal holes. This phenomenon causes mass loss in Wolf–Rayet stars. This phenomenon slows down abruptly at the termination shock, and it stops at the heliopause, where the interstellar medium begins. Comets’ ion tails always point away from a star due to this phenomenon. Charged particles in this substance interact with the Earth’s magnetosphere, producing auroras. For 10 points, name this stream of charged particles emitted from the outer regions of stars. ","answer":"ANSWER: stellar wind [or solar wind; prompt on interplanetary medium or IPM] <Other Science (Astronomy)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"5. This instrument played by Jean-Pierre Rampal and James Galway begins with descending and ascending chromatic notes in the Prelude to the Afternoon of a Faun. For 10 points, name this woodwind instrument, the larger sibling of the piccolo. ","answer":"ANSWER: flute <Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"1. In a novel by this author, a military historian who can write simultaneously backwards and forwards with both hands is one of the three friends who meet at the Toxique restaurant, where they see the supposedly long-dead Zenia. One of this writer’s protagonists recalls reading about “pig balls,” which are given to pigs who are being fattened for slaughter. One of this author’s characters used to be a televangelist on the Growing Souls Gospel Hour, and arranges for the protagonist to secretly have a relationship with Nick. In 2018 this author announced that her most popular novel would receive a sequel called The Testaments. In that novel, in which Unwomen are exiled to the colonies to clean up toxic waste, Offred (“OFF-red”) is forced to bear children for the Commander. For 10 points, name this author of The Robber Bride and The Handmaid’s Tale. ","answer":"ANSWER: Margaret Atwood [or Margaret Eleanor Atwood] <World Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"2. In some species, this compound contains pentaglycine bridges. This compound contains diaminopimelic acid, which covalently links to Braun’s lipoprotein. Teichoic (“tay-KO-ick”) acids are embedded within this compound and inhibit the action of autolysins on it. Changing one amino acid in this compound to lactate renders organisms resistant to vancomycin. DD-transpeptidases form crosslinks within this compound, whose subunits are transported by bactoprenol. This compound contains D-amino acids embedded within a polymer of N-acetylglucosamine and N-acetylmuramic acid. This compound takes up the crystal violet dye used in Gram staining. The assembly of this compound is inhibited by beta-lactam antibiotics like penicillin. For 10 points, name this polymer that forms the bacterial cell wall. ","answer":"ANSWER: peptidoglycan <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"3. Idaho Senator Len Jordan’s namesake rule was to vote the opposite way whenever this politician lobbied him to vote a certain way. This politician closed down historically-black Bowie State College during student riots and said that H. Rap Brown should be locked up and the key thrown away. This man described his enemies as “hopeless, hysterical hypochondriacs of history” and “nattering nabobs of negativism” in an address to Republicans in San Diego. This ethnic Greek was replaced in his highest position by a man who Lyndon B. Johnson called “too stupid to chew gum and walk at the same time.” This former Governor of Maryland resigned after he was accused of bribery and corruption, and was replaced by Gerald Ford. For 10 points, name this first Vice President under Richard Nixon. ","answer":"ANSWER: Spiro Agnew [or Spiro Theodore Agnew] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"4. E. Burke Rochford, a leading scholar of this movement, wrote an article for Social Problems discussing their recruitment practices. A member of this movement whose birth name was Keith Ham was accused of conspiring to murder two dissenters, but was acquitted thanks to a team led by Alan Dershowitz. The founder of this movement also founded a community near Wheeling, West Virginia, that is home to the Palace of Gold. Members of this movement often distribute a unique abridged version of a sacred text that adds the phrase “as it is” to the title. This movement is primarily known for its charitable Food for Life program and public street preaching. Founded by Swami Prabhupada, for 10 points, name this Hindu religious movement, named for a mantra to the eighth Avatar of Vishnu its adherents often chant. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hare Krishna movement [or the International Society for Krishna Consciousness or ISKCon] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"5. In one creation myth of these people, a god creates men from golden insects and women from silver insects, but is later eaten after turning into a deer, resulting in the creation of evil. After a ferryman refused to let three gods of disease enter the land of these people, a virgin goddess of these people severed his head and inflicted smallpox on his children. A semi-legendary king of these people was said to have been able to summon a bridge of turtles using his bow and arrow, and another king of these people was said to have been born after a tiger lost a contest to a bear who ate mugwort and garlic in a cave for 100 years. Mount Baekdu (“beck-doo”), a sacred site of these people, was the birthplace of their legendary king Dangun (“dahn-goon”). For 10 points, name these East Asian people who recorded their myths in the Samguk Yusa, which was written during the Goryeo (“gor-yuh”) dynasty. ","answer":"ANSWER: Koreans [accept Hanminjok or Hancha; accept answers referring to Jeju Island; accept Goryeo until read] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"6. An artist created a series of ten square one-and-a-half meter canvases, including one titled for how this city “was all gold,” for a 1961 exhibition in this city titled Art and Contemplation. A modern art museum in this city is housed in the former home of the American heiress Peggy Guggenheim. James Whistler painted his Nocturne in Blue and Silver during an extremely productive period of time in this city following his lawsuit against John Ruskin, who himself wrote a three-volume study of this city’s architecture. The workshop of Giovanni Bellini was located in this city, which gives its name to a “school” of artists that includes Giorgione (“jor-JO-nay”) and Tintoretto. Before he moved to England, Canaletto produced a number of incredibly accurate large-scale vedute (“veh-DOO-tay”) of, for 10 points, the Piazza San Marco and the Grand Canal in what Italian city? ","answer":"ANSWER: Venice [or Venezia; accept Venice Was All Gold and The Stones of Venice] <Painting> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"7. This playwright founded the small Intima Theater, where many of his plays were first performed. At the end of a play by this author, a young woman who complains about the drudgery of keeping the “filth of life” away disappears behind a screen as white light fills the room and a harp plays. One of this playwright’s characters is a “Sunday child,” which supposedly allows him to see people who others can’t, such as the apparition of a milkmaid. A character created by this man breaks off her engagement when her fiancé refuses to jump over a riding whip. In the same play by this author, a character is convinced to waltz with the title character and cheats on the cook Christine. In that play by this author, the valet Jean (“zhahn”) cuts off the head of the title character’s canary with a razor blade. For 10 points, name this Swedish playwright of The Ghost Sonata and Miss Julie. ","answer":"ANSWER: August Strindberg [or Johan August Strindberg] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"8. One group decided to oppose this military campaign when Ludwig Yorck von Wartenburg signed the Convention of Tauroggen. Three decades before Matthew Sankey created his first Sankey diagram, a “flow map” depicting six variables related to this campaign used line thickness to represent the number of soldiers in it. “Berezina” became a synonym for catastrophe among the instigators of this military campaign, since they suffered heavy losses while crossing the Berezina River. This campaign came to a climax at a battle in which attacks on the Bagration (“ba-gra-tee-OWN”) flèches (“flesh”) and the Raevsky Redoubt led to heavy losses on invading forces. Over 600,000 soldiers started this campaign but only 27,000 returned, many dying of cold during the retreat. For 10 points, the Battle of Borodino was part of what military campaign in which a country led by Alexander I was invaded by Napoleon? ","answer":"ANSWER: French invasion of Russia [or Patriotic War of 1812; accept Napoleon’s invasion of Russia until “Napoleon” is read; accept invasion of Russia after “Napoleon” is read; accept Second Polish War; prompt on Russian Campaign; prompt on Napoleonic Wars or Polish-Russian Wars] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"9. DOPE/CHEMS liposomes are sensitive to this quantity. BCECF-AM is used to measure this quantity in flow cytometry. A standard scale for this quantity relies on the Bates–Guggenheim convention to calculate the activity of chloride. Stable phases in an electrochemical solution are found by plotting potential against this quantity. Measurements of this quantity are confounded by the residual liquid junction potential. Carboranes and fluorinated antimony compounds are subject to the leveling effect, where solvent decreases this quantity, necessitating the use of the Hammett function instead. The value of this quantity for which an amino acid has zero net charge is the isoelectric point. It equals pKa plus the log of conjugate base over acid by the Henderson–Hasselbalch equation. Buffers keep this quantity constant. For 10 points, name this quantity equal to the log of the H-plus concentration. ","answer":"ANSWER: pH [prompt on acidity or basicity] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"0. This island’s two highest peaks are home to the El Tucuche golden tree frog, a variety of heart-tongued frog. This island was referred to as Iëre, deriving from a word for “hummingbird,” by its native Arawak inhabitants. The Lion House, the ancestral home of this island’s prominent Capildeo family, is located in its largest settlement, Chaguanas. The banning of African percussion instruments on this island in 1880 led to the development of the steelpan. This island is across the Gulf of Paria from Venezuela, making it the southernmost major island in the Caribbean. Supposedly, Christopher Columbus fulfilled a promise that he had made when he named this island after a religious concept after sighting three hills. The capital city of Port of Spain is on, for 10 points, what island which is much larger than its neighbor, Tobago? ","answer":"ANSWER: Trinidad <Geography> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"3. The Ottomans twice failed to capture, for 10 points, what capital of Austria? ","answer":"ANSWER: Vienna <European History> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this long poem by Ezra Pound whose title character tries to “maintain ‘the sublime’ in the old sense” and “resuscitate the dead art of poetry.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Hugh Selwyn Mauberley "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Mauberley is often compared to this character, who asks “Do I dare to eat a peach?” in a “love song” by T. S. Eliot. ","answer":"ANSWER: J. Alfred Prufrock [accept either underlined portion; accept “The Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Mauberley’s middle name may be an homage to Selwyn Image, a member of this group of British poets co-founded by W. B. Yeats. They met at a pub called Ye Olde Cheshire Cheese. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rhymers’ Club <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name these functions that give a way to calculate the inner product of vectors transformed into a different feature space. These functions can be based on polynomials or radial basis functions. ","answer":"ANSWER: kernel functions [accept kernel trick] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] SVMs are an example of a supervised model in this field of computer science that makes predictions based on sample “training” data. ","answer":"ANSWER: machine learning [or ML; prompt on, but DO NOT REVEAL, artificial intelligence or AI] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Support vector machines usually rely on an optimization algorithm named for “descending” in the direction given by this function. This function points toward local minima in parameter space. ","answer":"ANSWER: gradient [accept stochastic gradient descent] <Other Science (Computer Science)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Tate Modern houses Cage, a set of six square abstract paintings produced in 2006 by this artist with the help of a squeegee. He painted his daughter Betty looking away from the viewer in a 1988 portrait of her. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gerhard Richter "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The subtitle of this man’s painting Blue With China Ink notes that it is an homage to John Cage, with whom he was a co-editor of the art journal Possibilities. This abstract expressionist painted the series Elegy to the Spanish Republic. ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Motherwell "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marcel Duchamp (“dew-SHOM”) <Painting> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The 26th of July Movement overthrew this dictator, whose regime killed tens of thousands of people while giving away his country’s key industries and resources to the United States. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fulgencio Batista [or Fulgencio Batista y Zaldívar; or Rubén Zaldívar] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The 26th of July Movement was led by this man, who took power after the fall of Batista. He would rule Cuba for the next fifty or so years, before passing power to his brother Raúl. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fidel Castro [or Fidel Alejandro Castro Ruz] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"3. ","answer":"ANSWER: Moncada Barracks <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this syncretic Caribbean religion known as the “worship of saints” that is a combination of Roman Catholicism and Yoruban (“YOR-oo-bin”) beliefs. ","answer":"ANSWER: Santería "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] This sacred language of Santería is a variety of the Yoruba language. The namesake people of this language share their traditional healing practice in Santería rituals. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lucumí "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] An ordinance against this Santería practice was declared unconstitutional in Church of the Lukumi Babalu Aye v. City of Hialeah. In Judaism, this practice is known as korban (“kor-BAHN”). ","answer":"ANSWER: animal sacrifice [accept chicken sacrifice; prompt on sacrifice; prompt on killing animals] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this democratic socialist representative of New York’s 14th congressional district, the youngest woman ever to serve in Congress. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez [or AOC] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Ocasio-Cortez pulled off a stunning upset in her campaign against this ten-term incumbent, who was at the time the Chair of the House Democratic Caucus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Joe Crowley [or Joseph Crowley] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] In the general election, Crowley was still on the ballot as the nominee of the Women’s Equality Party and this other New York-based minor left-wing party, despite its executive director Dan Cantor explicitly endorsing Ocasio-Cortez. ","answer":"ANSWER: Working Families Party [or WFP] <Current Events> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this three-word sentence that exposes the fact that the relationships between fictional women are often very simple, and that fictional women are “almost without exception… shown in their relation to men.” ","answer":"ANSWER: “Chloe liked Olivia” "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The phrase “Chloe liked Olivia” is discussed in this essay, which imagines what would have happened to the hypothetical Judith Shakespeare. ","answer":"ANSWER: A Room of One’s Own "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] A Room of One’s Own was written by this author of To the Lighthouse and Mrs Dalloway. ","answer":"ANSWER: Virginia Woolf [or Adeline Virginia Stephen] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] One consequence of the South Sea Bubble was this man’s rise to power as the first British Prime Minister. ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Walpole, 1st Earl of Orford "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] This Chancellor of the Exchequer was forced to resign for his role in the South Sea Bubble. This man was a strong supporter of the plan for the South Sea Company to take over the national debt in exchange for government bonds. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Aislabie (“AYZ-luh-bee”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The failure of the South Sea Company led to the pre-eminence of this institution, often called “the old lady of Threadneedle Street.” George Soros was known as the man who “broke” this institution after he short-sold 10 billion dollars in pounds on Black Wednesday. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bank of England <British History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name these diagrams used to predict absorption bands in coordination complexes. The x- and y-axes of these diagrams are scaled by the Racah parameter B. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tanabe–Sugano (“tah-nah-bay soo-gah-no”) diagrams "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Unlike Orgel diagrams, Tanabe–Sugano diagrams apply to complexes with either a high or a low value for this quantity. A high value for this quantity corresponds to a low field strength, and vice versa. ","answer":"ANSWER: spin "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Tanabe–Sugano diagram for complexes with this number of d electrons does not exist, because the d orbitals are completely filled and thus there are no transitions between them. This is the atomic number of neon. ","answer":"ANSWER: 10 <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name these parsed corpora in linguistics that are created by annotating either phrase structures or dependency structures in a body of texts. ","answer":"ANSWER: treebanks [prompt on corpora or corpus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Penn Treebank project created the most popular of the namesake “sets” for tagging these linguistic categories, which include nouns, verbs, and adjectives. ","answer":"ANSWER: parts of speech [or POS; accept part of speech tagging or POST; prompt on lexical categories] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Corpus linguists often analyze the occurrence of these sets of co-occurring words within a given window of text. Jon Orwant and Will Brockman used the Google Books corpus to develop a program that displays the frequencies of these things over time. ","answer":"ANSWER: n-grams [accept the Google Books Ngram Viewer; anti-prompt on bigrams, trigrams, etc. by asking “can you be less specific?”] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name these Spanish religious outposts in California, the first of which were founded by Junípero Serra (“hoo-NEE-pay-roh SAIR-ah”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Spanish missions in California [or misiones] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"0. San Francisco Bay was first sighted by this man’s expedition. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gaspar de Portolà [or Gaspar de Portolà y Rovira] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Portolà expedition founded this capital of Alta California under Spanish and Mexican rule. John Sloat captured this city in 1846 during the Mexican-American War, claiming California for the United States. ","answer":"ANSWER: Monterey <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this novel by José Maria de Eça de Queiroz (“zhoo-ZAY mah-REE-ah dee EH-sah dee kay-ROHSH”) about the decline of the title family. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Maias: Episodes of Romantic Life [or Os Maias: Episódios da Vida Romântica] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Eça de Queiroz is an author from this country. The author of Blindness, José Saramago (“zhoo-ZAY sah-rah-MAH-goo”), is also from this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: Portugal [or Portuguese Republic; or República Portuguesa] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] In 1995, Saramago received this prize, the most important prize given to authors who write in Portuguese. It’s named for the author of an epic poem about Vasco da Gama. ","answer":"ANSWER: Camões (“kah-MOISH”) Prize [or Prémio Camões; accept Camoens Prize] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this phenomenon in which the topology of magnetic field lines changes, releasing energy. One form of this process happens faster than predicted by MHD. ","answer":"ANSWER: magnetic reconnection "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Magnetic reconnection happens in highly conductive examples of these systems, which are hot ionized gases. ","answer":"ANSWER: plasma "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Magnetic field lines are “frozen in” to conductive plasma because charged particles undergo this type of motion in a uniform magnetic field due to the Lorentz force. Particles move in circular orbits with angular frequency q times B over m in this type of motion. ","answer":"ANSWER: cyclotron motion [accept cyclotron orbits; prompt on circular motion or similar descriptions] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this composition. The soloist in this piece opens with the notes “D, long low B, [pause] C, long low E,” over G major arpeggios in the harp. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harold in Italy [or Harold en Italie] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Harold in Italy was written by this French composer of The Damnation of Faust and Symphonie Fantastique. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hector Berlioz [or Louis-Hector Berlioz] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] This musician commissioned Harold in Italy after acquiring a new viola. This man also composed a piece which inspired Franz Liszt’s La Campanella étude. ","answer":"ANSWER: Niccolò Paganini <Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this city first ruled by Sisyphus, who founded its Isthmian Games. While in this city, Jason abandoned his wife Medea to marry its princess, Glauce (“glossy”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Corinth "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Sisyphus earned his divine punishment by putting Thanatos, the god of this concept, in chains. Humans who had recently undergone this experience crossed the river Styx in a ferry driven by Charon (“karen”). ","answer":"ANSWER: death "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Greek heroes making a visit to the underworld are often depicted observing Sisyphus and other criminals suffering in Tartarus. This is the Greek name for the mytheme (“MYTH-eem”) in which heroes journey to the underworld. ","answer":"ANSWER: katabasis <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this Byzantine emperor, the husband of Theodora. He put down the Nika Revolts. ","answer":"ANSWER: Justinian "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] This historian from Caesarea wrote a “Secret History” of Justinian’s reign, which probably exaggerated or made up many atrocities that Justinian supposedly committed. ","answer":"ANSWER: Procopius "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Justinian’s reign is considered to be part of this two-word historical period from 150 to 750 AD. It was popularized by a 1971 Peter Brown book that discusses this period as the transition between the ancient and medieval worlds. ","answer":"ANSWER: late antiquity [accept The World of Late Antiquity] <Ancient History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this thesis which holds that mental states, such as pain, can be instantiated in different kinds of systems. ","answer":"ANSWER: multiple realizability [or multiple realization thesis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The concept of multiple realizability was introduced to the philosophy of mind in a series of articles by this thinker, who used his “Twin Earth” thought experiment to argue for semantic externalism. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hilary Putnam "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Empirical arguments for multiple realizability often appeal to developments in computer-based cognitive functioning in this two-word field. John Searle criticized the “strong” form of a thesis named for this concept in his Chinese Room argument. ","answer":"ANSWER: artificial intelligence [or AI; accept Strong AI] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this novel in which a clairvoyant character predicts the death of Rosa the Beautiful. ","answer":"ANSWER: The House of the Spirits [or La casa de los espíritus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The House of the Spirits is by this Chilean novelist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Isabel Allende [or Isabel Allende Llona] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The novel ends with the revelation that this character is pregnant, as she sits with the dead body of Esteban Trueba. She is the daughter of Blanca and Pedro Tercero. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alba Trueba de Satigny <World Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name these cytoskeletal components that are polymers of tubulin arranged in a 13-fold symmetric hollow cylinder. They form the mitotic spindle. ","answer":"ANSWER: microtubules "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] These molecular motors move towards the negative end of microtubules. They link microtubules together in flagella, and they are responsible for retrograde axonal transport. ","answer":"ANSWER: dyneins (“DYNE-ins”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Lysine-40 on alpha-tubulin can undergo this chemical modification, which stabilizes microtubules. GNATs like GCN5 catalyze the addition of this group to a different protein, a modification recognized by bromodomains. ","answer":"ANSWER: acetyl [or ethanoyl; or acetylation or ethanoylation] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this servant who repeatedly punctuates the opening aria “Notte e giorno faticar” (“NOTE-tay ay JOR-no fah-tee-CAR”) with “No no no no no.” This character also details the romantic conquests of his master in the “Catalogue Aria.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Leporello "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Leporello appears in this opera by Mozart that ends with the title nobleman being dragged to hell by a statue of the murdered Commendatore. ","answer":"ANSWER: Don Giovanni [or Il dissoluto punito; ossia, il Don Giovanni; or The Rake Punished, or Don Giovanni; or The Libertine Punished, or Don Giovanni] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Commendatore drags Don Giovanni to hell after Don Giovanni had earlier performed this action because Leporello was too frightened to do it himself. The statue bellows out an affirmative “Si” after this proposal. ","answer":"ANSWER: invites the statue to dinner [or offers him an evening meal; or equivalents; prompt on invites him to his house (or equivalents)] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this French author who included the novel Le Père Goriot (“luh pair gor-YO”) in his collection The Human Comedy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Honoré de Balzac "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] In a novel from The Human Comedy, Raphaël de Valentin (“val-on-TAN”) acquires a magical wish-granting piece of the skin of one of these animals. ","answer":"ANSWER: wild ass [accept The Wild Ass’s Skin] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"N","question":"[10] The original title of The Wild Ass’s Skin puns on this French word, which can refer either to a particular type of hide or to an emotion. ","answer":"ANSWER: chagrin <European Literature>"}]
